MAKSYM MALTSEV



maksym.maltsev@gmail.com +971 56 272 3172





linkedin.com/in/maksymmaltsev/



maltsev_m90



Dubai, United Arab Emirates

SUMMARY

Highly capable E-commerce Consultant / Project Manager with 7+ years of UAE experience across Retail, Banking and Hospitality sectors, seeking to leverage proven leadership, strategy and business analysis skills to drive digital transformation or digital operations.

EXPERTISE

E-commerce Operations Project Management Strategy Definition

Omnichannel Commerce Programme Management Market Research

Software Testing Stakeholders Management **Business Analysis**

ORGANISATIONS AND CLIENTS













WORK EXPERIENCE

AZUR DIGITAL, DUBAI, UAE

E-commerce Consultant / Project Manager E-commerce Business Analyst

Sep 2018 - Present Jun 2017 - Sep 2018

Achievements:

• Successfully delivered on-site Omnichannel transformation programme for a leading supermarket chain in Mauritius in 6 months

Responsibilities:

Project Management:

- Performing on-site and remote Project Management using different methodologies (Agile, Waterfall) for various retail clients, this includes: stakeholders management, tasks and timelines management, resources management, running weekly update meetings and more
- Using JIRA as a collaboration tool between business and third party software development teams
- Planning development Sprints with accordance to the defined features roadmap

WORK EXPERIENCE

E-commerce Operations:

- Conducting client workshops to define detailed omnichannel requirements and specifications (e.g. checkout funnel, fraud monitoring, reports, fulfillment process, reverse logistics, etc)
- Designing e-commerce processes and assisting client teams in implementing the needed operations changes (e.g. customer service, fulfillment, content management, etc)
- Providing insights on industry best practice and experiences to guide and facilitate decision-making while ensuring alignment of people and processes with technological solutions and integrations Business Analysis:
- Defining Omnichannel strategy, value proposition, customer experience, functional architecture and roadmap, operational setup and organisational implications for international retailers
- Partners/Vendors search: RFP preparation, evaluation and selection
- Coordinating integration between EPR, payment gateway and e-commerce platforms
- Documenting Epics and User Stories based on functional architecture and roadmap
- Conducting market research on various topics: e-commerce solutions, vendors, trends and writing articles for omnichannel commerce blog

Programme Management:

- Part of Programme Management Office (PMO) on multi-stream large scale (10M+ USD) projects;
- Running Project Committee meetings with stakeholders and Executive Committee with CEO/ Programme Sponsor; Documenting progress, risks, decisions

Software Testing:

- Working in an Agile environment performing functional (unit testing, integration testing, sanity check) and maintenance (regression) testing in various e-commerce platforms (SAP Hybris);
- Identifying, reporting and tracking product defects in Jira/Zephyr

NATIONAL BANK OF ABU DHABI, ABU DHABI, UAE

Customer Experience Data Analyst

Customer Experience System Coordinator

Service Ambassador

Apr 2016 - Mar 2017

Feb 2015 - Apr 2016

Mar 2014 - Feb 2015

Achievements:

- Selected twice as an Employee of the Month (Oct 2015 and May 2016)
- In cooperation with IT successfully managed the delivery of two internal web-based applications from scratch for staff recognition and target management
- Acted as a Product Owner for Complaints Management System (CMS) across the bank budgeting, enhancements and features roadmap, training delivery, user management and support
- Successfully rolled out Complaints Management System to International regions (Oman, Egypt, UK)
- Delivered multiple CMS training sessions for 50+ staff

ST. REGIS SAADIYAT ISLAND RESORT, ABU DHABI, UAE

Front Office Associate

Human Resources Coordinator (Pre-opening team)

Feb 2012 - Mar 2014

Sep 2011 - Feb 2012

EDUCATION

BA of Engineering, SNA University, Ukraine